petsadviser.com 2019-05-06

# Privacy Policy

### We Use Cookies

Please note that our website uses “cookies” to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can be read only by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

For more detailed information about how we use cookies, please review the “Use of Cookies” section below.

### Non-Personal Information

We share or disclose non-personal data, such as aggregated information like the total number of times people viewed an article on our site, the number of people who clicked on a particular link, or how many people saw or clicked on an ad.

### Security of Your Personal Information

Petful.com secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We use encryption (HTTPS/TLS) to protect data transmitted to and from our site. However, no data transmission over the internet is 100% secure, so we can’t guarantee security. You use our site and services at your own risk, and you’re responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your account.

If you leave a comment on our site, we encourage you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Petful.com so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites other than our own.

We will never sell or distribute any personal or contact information we collect about you. We do not sell, rent or lease our customer lists to third parties.

Petful will disclose your personal information, without notice, _only_ if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on us; (b) protect and defend our rights or property; and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

Petful uses third-party vendors and hosting partners, such as [SiteGround](https://www.siteground.com/privacy.htm) and [Cloudflare](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/), for hardware, software, networking, storage and related technology we need to run our site. When you use or interact with any of our services, you consent to the data processing, sharing, transferring and uses of your information as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Regardless of the country where you reside, you authorize us to transfer, process, store and use your information in countries other than your own in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to provide you with services. Some of these countries may not have the same data protection safeguards as the country where you reside.

Although we are a U.S.-based website intended for users located in the United States, Petful may process information related to individuals who are in the EU/European Economic Area. We may transfer that information from the EU/EEA to the United States or any other country where we have facilities. By using our services, you consent to the transfer of information outside of your country.

If you are located in the EU/EEA, you can request access to the information we hold about you. We’ll usually share this with you within 30 days of you asking us for it. The first time is free, and additional requests may incur a reasonable processing fee. You may also request modification or deletion of your personal data.

### Use of Cookies

One way that we collect information from you is through the use of cookies. When you go online, you use a program called a “browser” (like Apple Safari or Google Chrome). Most websites store a small amount of text in the browser — and that text is called a “cookie.”

Cookies provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to our website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved so you can easily use the features that you customized.

We use cookies to make Petful better. For example, these cookies tell us how many people use a certain feature and how popular it is, or whether people open an email we send.

We also use cookies to help advertisers understand who sees and interacts with their ads, and who visits their website or purchases their products.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our website. Most browsers let you block “third-party cookies,” which are cookies from sites other than the one you’re visiting.

Our website may also use small pieces of software code called "web beacons" ("pixel tags") to collect anonymous and aggregate data, such as counting page views or advertising responses. A web beacon is an electronic image constructed from a single-pixel or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information, such as your IP address, cookie number, time and date of a page view, and description of the page where the web beacon is placed. You may render some web beacons unusable if you choose to reject their associated cookies.

### Advertising Cookies and Web Beacons

Here’s the deal. We _have_ to make money at Petful to keep our website running, pay our writers for their work and provide free, high-quality resources to our users. We want to deliver ads that are relevant, interesting and personal to you in order to pay our bills. For example, if you visit a page about dog food (or have visited one in the past), you may see an ad for a brand of dog food.

Third-party vendors, such as Google through the AdSense program, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to Petful.com or other websites. This use of advertising cookies enables these vendors to serve ads to you based on your visit to this site and/or other sites on the internet. You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

If you click on an ad or external link, that advertiser or website operator might figure out that you came from Petful, along with other information associated with the ad you clicked such as characteristics of the audience it was intended to reach. That entity may also collect other personal data from you, such as cookie identifiers or your IP address.

 **Petful’s advertising partners include:**

  * [ **Google**](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) **:** Petful.com collects data about your activities that does not personally or directly identify you when you visit our website, the website of entities for which we serve advertisements (our “Advertisers”), or the websites and online services where we display advertisements (“Publishers”). This information may include the content you view, the date and time that you view this content, the products you purchase, or your location information associated with your IP address. We use the information we collect to serve you more relevant advertisements (referred to as “Retargeting”). We collect information about where you saw the ads we serve you and what ads you clicked on. You can opt out by visiting Google’s [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) or the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).
  * [ **Amazon**](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496) **:** Petful is a participant in the [Amazon Services LLC Associates Program](https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/gp/associates/join/landing/main.html), an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

 **Our other advertising partners include:**

### Cookie Declaration

Cookie declaration last updated Feb. 4, 2019, by Cookiebot: [Download here](https://www.petful.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cookies.pdf) (PDF).

### How Long We Keep Your Information

We keep your information only so long as we need it to provide our services to you and fulfill the purposes described in this policy. This is also the case for anyone we share your information with and who carries out services on our behalf. When we no longer need to use your information and there is no need for us to keep it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, we’ll either remove it from our systems or depersonalize it so that we can’t identify you.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. [See more here](https://consumercal.org/about-cfc/cfc-education-foundation/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa-3/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf).

According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously.
  * Once this Privacy Policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or at a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word "Privacy," and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

  * On this Privacy Policy page

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us or using the Privacy Controls in the table below.

 **How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**

Some internet browsers may be configured to send "Do Not Track" signals to the online services that you visit. There currently is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Therefore, like many websites and online services, we do not alter our practices when we receive a "Do Not Track" signal from your browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," [visit this page](https://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

 **Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

Yes, we do allow third-party behavioral tracking, which we described above.

 **Does our site share personal data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes?**

No, Petful does not share personal data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, unless we give you a choice (opt in or opt out) before sharing with those third parties.

### Children Under 13

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

Petful does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

### CAN-SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to:

  * Send you our free [pet food recall alerts](https://www.petful.com/newsletter/) (only if we have first obtained your permission)

We collect this information from you when you fill out a form on our site.

To be in accordance with CAN-SPAM, we agree to the following:

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can unsubscribe using the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email we send you, or contact us using our [Contact Page](https://www.petful.com/contact/), and we will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

### Change of Ownership

In the event that we are involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your personal data may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. This Privacy Policy will apply to your personal data as transferred to the new entity.

### Privacy Controls

At Petful, we believe that the best user experience is a personalized one. Here are some ways you can control your experience:

Control| Links  
---|---  
View Petful without recording webpages and files in your browser.| Use your browser's "private" setting, such as [Incognito](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?hl=en) in Chrome  
View, manage and/or delete cookies in your browser.| [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en), [Safari](https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/), [Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/278835/how-to-delete-cookie-files-in-internet-explorer), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored)  
Prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics.| [Opt-Out Add-On](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)  
Edit or delete your comments underneath our articles.| [Disqus](https://disqus.com/profile/login/)  
Unsubscribe from our emails if you opted in.| Unsubscribe link at bottom of email  
We attempt to match the advertising you see on Petful with your interests based on your online activities and expressed preferences. Manage each interest or opt out of personalized advertising.| [Ad Choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/) or [Opt Out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)  
Any other questions or concerns you may have.| [Contact Us](https://www.petful.com/contact/)  
  
### Changes to This Policy

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. We encourage you to periodically review this page to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

### Contact Information

Here is who is responsible for your personal data:

Attn: Privacy Policy Inquiry  
Super Copy Editors LLC  
116 Conselyea St. #3A  
Brooklyn NY 11211

Email Address:  

 _Last updated: May 2, 2019_

 **See Also:** [Petful.com Terms and Conditions](https://www.petful.com/terms-of-use-agreement/)
